ABU TAREQ RONY

% Medium.com/Abu Tareq Rony Github/Abu Tareq Rony

▼ Fiverr.com/AbuTareqRony

□ rony1513@student.nstu.edu.bd **?**Dhaka, Bangladesh

\+88 01882793501

ABOUT ME

Abu Tareq Rony is a diligent individual who is self-taught in Natural Language Processing, Large Language Models, Statistics, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning. He has 3.5 years of research experience and published articles in refereed journals and conference proceedings such as IEEE, Elsevier, Springer, and various international conferences. He achieved a TGPA of 3.99 and secured the second merit position in his final semester, with an overall CGPA of 3.56 out of 4.0. Moreover, He has served as a Reviewer for Elsevier, Springer, IEEE Access, and Wiley, and has reviewed more than 20 research papers. He is dedicated to pursuing an academic career in LLM, AI, NLP, Statistics, and Deep Learning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Jan 2024 — Present **Data Science Instructor**

aiQuest Intelligence

• Responsible for working as an Instructor and taking Live sessions on Research Methodology, and Courses on Statistics for Data Science.

Dec 2020 — Present **Data Scientist**

Fiverr Link

• Level 2 seller on Fiverr, I am a Data Scientist and Business Analyst offering services for more than three years and have completed 250+ projects on Fiverr. I provide high-quality service for Statistics, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, LLMs, Deep Learning, and much more.

Dec 2021 — Present

2024

Data Science Blog Writter

Medium Link

• Write articles on NLP, LLMs, Statistics, Machine learning, and Data Science.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

$\mathrm{Dec}\ 2018 -\!\!\!\!\!-\mathrm{Dec}\ 2023$	Bachelor of Science(BSc), Department of Statistics	CGPA: $3.56(4)$
	\bullet Noakhali Science and Technology University (NSTU), Bangladesh.	
Jan 2014 — June 2016	Higher Secondary School Certificate, Chittagong Board	GPA: 4.58(5)
	• Omar Gani M.E.S College, Bangladesh.	
$\mathrm{Jan}\ 2013 - \mathrm{Dec}\ 2014$	Secondary School Certificate, Chittagong Board	GPA: $5.00(5)$
	• Kattali N.H.C High School, Bangladesh.	

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS [80 Citations]

2024 MediGPT: Exploring Potentials of Conventional and Large Language Models on Medical Data—Link

• IEEE Access, Q1

Elevating Driver Behavior Understanding With RKnD: A Novel Probabilistic Feature Engineering Approach—Link

• IEEE Access, Q1

2023	BNVGLENET: Hypercomplex Bangla handwriting character recognition with hierarchical class expansion using Convolutional Neural Networks— Link
	• Natural Language Processing Journal, Elsevier
2024	Evaluating Large Language Models for Summarizing Bangla Texts— $Link(Accepted)$
	• EMNLP Workshop 2024, USA
2024	BanVATLLM and BanTSS: A Multimodal Framework and a Dataset for Detecting Toxic Speech in Bangla and Bangla-English Videos— Link(Accepted)
	• EMNLP Workshop 2024, USA
2024	A Novel Deep Learning Approach for Accurate Cancer Type and Subtype Identification—Link
	• IEEE Access, Q1
2023	Machine Learning-Based Rainfall Prediction: Unveiling Insights and Forecasting for Improved Preparedness— Link
	• IEEE Access, Q1
2023	CBD2023: A Hypercomplex Bangla Handwriting Character Recognition Data for Hierarchical Class Expansion— ${\rm Link}$
	• Data in Brief, Q2 , Elsevier
2024	A Novel Deep Learning Approach for Forecasting Myocardial Infarction Occurrences with Time Series Patient Data — $Link$
	• Journal of Medical Systems, Q1, Springer
2024	Beyond Words: Unraveling Text Complexity with Novel Dataset and A Classifier Application— Link
	• ICCIT-24, IEEE
2024	The Multi-Class Paradigm: How Transformers are Reshaping Language Analysis in NLP—Link
	• Lecture Notes in Computer Science, TEHI-23, Springer
2023	An Innovative Novel Transformer Model and Datasets for Safeguarding Religious Sensitivities in Online Social Platforms— Link
	• Procedia Computer Science, Elsevier
2024	GastroVRG: Enhancing Early Screening in Gastrointestinal Health via Advanced Transfer Features— $Link$
	• Intelligent Systems with Applications, Q1, Elsevier
SUBMITTED P	PAPERS
2024	Empowering Low-Resource Languages: TraSe Architecture for Enhanced Retrieval-Augmented Generation in Bangla— $Link$
	• EMNLP Workshop 2024, USA
2024	Bangla ViTa: A Novel Multimodal Fusion Approach to Bangla Troll Memes Identification— Link
	• IEEE Access, Q1
2024	BdSentiLLM: A Novel LLM Approach to Sentiment Analysis of Product Reviews in Bangladeshi Contexts— Link

• IEEE Access, Q1

• IEEE Access, Q1

2024

SumGPT: An Improved Multimodal Radiology Report Summarization to Optimize Clinical Efficiency— Link

2024 Improving Abstract Screening Efficiency with Transformer-Based Models an	d Zero-Shot
---	-------------

Learning—Link

• EMNLP Workshop 2024, USA

2024 DMLRS: A Novel AI-Based Identification of Autism Spectrum Disorder with Explainable Features and Smart Web Application— Link

• IEEE Access, Q1

\$\Psi\$ SKILLSETS AND PROFICIENCIES

Code Languages Python, R. C Program- IDE Jupyter, Google Colab.	Code Languages	Jupyter, Google Colab, RStu-
---	----------------	------------------------------

ming(Basic), Latex dio, Pycharm, VS code

Data Analysis Excel, SPSS, STATA, EViews Graphic Design Figma, Adobe Photoshop,

Data Mining Weka Canva

Data Visualization PowerBI, Tableau, Matplotlib, Learning Large Language Model, RAG,

FowerBi, Tableau, Matplotino,
Seaborn, ggplot2, Google Data

Computer Vision, Audio Processing, Streamlight, Multi-

Studio model, etc.

Machine Learning Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Pytorch Soft Skills Project Management, Writing,

Cn Public Speaking

ACHIEVEMENTS

Mar 2023 Paper Reviewer

• Pattern Recognition, Elsevier • Expert Systems with Applications, Elsevier

• Artificial Intelligence In Medicine, **Elsevier** • IEEE Access, etc. April 2022 Scholarship

• The scholarship is awarded based on my final semester results and academic activities at NSTU.

April 2022 Best Research Paper Award

• Received the Best Research Paper Award at ICETET- SIP 22.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Jan 2021 — Jun 2021 NSTU Statistics Assosiation Executive Member

Mar 2020 — Dec 2020 IT Club, NSTU General Secretary

REFERENCES

Md. Rasel Hossain

Assistant Professor, Department of Statistics (NSTU)

Email: rasel.stat@nstu.edu.bd

■ DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all information provided above is correct, complete, and true to the best of my knowledge

Abu Tareq Rony

Abu Tareq Rony